COLLINS MAGONDU MUTHINJA

Nairobi, Kenya (+254) 753924 273 / (+254) 708402798 Portfolio Link collinsmuthinja@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Personal Statement

An agile, all-rounded and experienced software engineer focused on creating clean, maintainable, and consistent software solutions for both for-profit and non-profit businesses. I also create software used in embedded systems as a hobby.

Highlighted Software Applications

Tripitaca's Web Application (Nuxt & NestJS) - Tripitaca

June 2021 - Present

I architectured and designed Tripitaca's web application and cloud infrastructure. I lead Tripitaca's technology team and am the de facto code reviewer for every pull request on all our code bases.

- 1. Nest JS (Node JS Server Side Framework)
- 2. Vue JS
- 3. Google Cloud Platform
- 4. MongoDB
- 5. Flutterwave
- 6. Nuxt JS

Check the website at www.tripitaca.com

USSD Application - Boda Care Insurance

March 2021 - August 2021

Dial *483*204#

Designed and developed Boda Care's USSD application, Backend, and Web Portal

- 1. Nest JS
- 2. Java Spark
- 3. Africa's Talking
- 4. Angular
- 5. MySQL
- 6. Google Cloud Platform

M-TIBA Ussd Redesign - Carepay Limited Dial *253#

March 2019 - October 2019

Redesigned USSD screens for the M-TIBA Platform while working for Carepay

• Spring Boot (Java Framework)

- Docker (Containerization Tool)
- CI Tool (Bitbucket Pipelines)
- BDD Testing Tool (Cucumber)

Chess MVP (Android App and Web Application) - Iconic King Limited

March 2019

Android App URL https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=chessbet.app.com/
Web Application https://chessbet-app-com-v1.firebaseapp.com/#/home/landing
Github Link https://github.com/iconic-king/chess-bet.git
Youtube Videohttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iRaJuurQfBU

An android and web-based chess learning and playing platform created from scratch.

- A UCI Engine Support For Play Vs Computer (Stockfish)
- Java Android App
- Node JS (Cloud Functions) matching and challenge acceptance algorithm for online play created from scratch
- Google Cloud Platform for the cloud architecture
- Travis CI used as our CI/CD tool
- Github VCS
- Angular 9, Angular Material, Bootstrap, and JS for the web application
- A Typescript and Java-based chess engine created from scratch

URL https://chess-bet.com/

P2P chess betting Android Application created for all levels of chess players.

- Mpesa Daraja API for C2B and B2B transactions
- Nest JS for the payments backend
- Google Cloud Platform for the cloud hosting
- MySQL as the accounts and transactions DB
- TypeORM as the Object Relational Mapping tool
- Cloud Functions for matching and challenge creation algorithm
- Java-based android application

Falcon One (DIY Drone) - Final Project At Moringa School

January 2019

URL https://github.com/zecollokaris/Remote-Control-Falcon-1-Quadcopter

Drone controlled by an Android application connected via WI-FI and TCP/IP protocol. It has 3 main units hardware, firmware, and the mobile application

- Java Programming Language (For the android application)
- C Programming Language (For the flight controller system)
- MPU-6050
- ESP-8266 Node MCU
- Quadcopter Kit

Agrino - Personal Project

November 2018

URL: https://github.com/Magz8984/Agrino

An android application to inform farmers of services around their location, share information with other farmers, and gain knowledge from reading article updates. Technologies used and relevant are

- XML defining layouts and resources used in my app not forgetting the manifest
- Java The engineering language behind the functionality of the app
- Circular image View dependency to create my recycler-view item circular Image
- Glide To ensure smooth image loading since images are retrieved from the Internet
- Firebase SaaS utilities such as firebase storage to store images and other documents, firebase real-time database to store user captions and account preferences.

URL: https://magz8984.github.io/Build/

A Linux and Windows C program dedicated to helping develop the basic program structure of gradle-managed java apps. This tool saw use in Moringa school by Java students and was even preferred by others than how IDEs such as IntelliJ build Gradle applications. The reason for this is.

- It created an easy to follow projects structure
- Included a custom Heroku procfile.
- Created a build Gradle script based on user preferences.

Technical Skills

Strong: Javascript, Typescript, C, Java, HTML, CSS, Postgresql, MySQL, SQL, Spark, Mastercard API, PayPal API, MPESA Daraja API, MongoDB, Flutterwave, Git, NoSQL, Nest JS, Vue, Nuxt JS, Google Cloud Platform, Serverless Technology.

Experienced: Python, PHP, React JS, Angular JS, Angular, Nest JS, Type ORM, Cloud Functions, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase, Travis CI, C/C++, Java, Nest JS

Personal Skills

- Creative problem solver, I find it rather easy to create solutions that are flexible, easily understandable, and adaptable for even the most complex of problems.
- I'm a fast learner who easily adapts to change.
- Vigilant and pays attention to detail.

Employment History

Tripitaca Bookings Lead Architect

June 2021 - Till Date

Achivements and Responsibilities

- I came up with the application architecture and stack that is currently being used.
- I single-handedly developed the first backend version for Tripitaca
- By introducing a program that ensured every team member learned a new skill every week I challenged my team members to become better managers and programmers.

Iconic King Lead Developer

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

Achievements and Responsibilities

- I lead the software development team developing POS and ERP Systems.
- Had an active role in API development, Frontend development, Android application development and Interfacing various payments gateways.

Carepay Limited

Software Developer and Support Developer

March 2019 - October 2019

Achievements and Responsibilities

- I was in charge of the technical line of support for all technical queries from M-TIBA's customers
- Redesigned MTIBA's USSD Application (Dial *253#)
- Assisted in redesigning M-TIBA's Provider Portal
- Assisted in creating an account renewal system

Freelancer and Trainer

May 2017 - Present

Achievements and Responsibilities

- Helped students interested in learning programming concepts get to speed with the ever-changing technology.
- Creating content on youtube and helping interested students learn web design. (https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwdiZiDNen4Y6V9fIQ9Va8Q/videos)

Academic Qualification

Moringa School May 2018 - February 2019 Web Design and Software Engineering (Android)

Jomo Kenyatta University September 2018 Bachelor Of Science Computer Science

Institute Of Advanced Technology March 2017 - June 2017 VB.NET and Java Programming

Professional Qualification

Great Learning (Recent)

July 2022

Award: Certification In Intermediate Java Developer Data Structures and Algorithms

Institute Of Advanced Technology March-June 2017

Award: Certified Java Developer.

Institute Of Advanced Technology

March-June 2017

Award: Certified VB .NET Developer

Interests

- Playing and teaching chess, I find it interesting and mind engaging.
- Hiking: I love the outdoors.
- Reading articles and non-fiction books and memoirs, currently, I am reading the 10X Rule by Grant Cardone
- Writing technology and startup articles on Medium. (Follow me on https://muthinja.medium.com)
- Languages: English (expert) and Swahili (expert).
- A recently acquired interest has been adding to my professional certifications

References

Timothy Murithi

Director

CEO

Boda Care

Tel: (+254) 724065160

Email: muthinja2003@yahoo.com

Apollo Kariuki

Software Engineer at Microsoft (My Supervisor at Carepay . Was Lead Developer)

Tel: (+254) 720681119

George Komen

Senior Software Engineer Andela

Tel: (+254) 713014492

Peter Kariuki

Lead Developer Iconic King

Tel: (+254) 798731203

Joyce Wambui

Technical Mentor Moringa School

Tel: (+254)714895623

Email: joyce.wambui@moringaschool.com